hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Krakowski I'm thankful that
you're here this podcast is for coaches
trainers mentors authors and thought
leaders who want to get more clients in
their business make more money and live
the life of their dreams now today I
want to talk about a topic that I've
been thinking about for a while and it's
so important it applies to every single
aspect of your business did you know
that your pricing has to do with your
boundaries that you have let me explain
this boundaries is such an important
part of the process as a coach as a
mentor and not allowing other people to
encroach upon those and to be able to
control what we will do and won't do
that it goes down to even our pricing
let me explain this if you're like
I you know I don't know if I could
charge more than five hundred dollars
for my coaching that means that that's
your boundary to which you are willing
to help other people and Coach them and
that that your boundary is at 500
financially mine is at two thousand
dollars financially for group coaching
and over fifteen thousand dollars for
one-on-one coaching that's my boundary
some of you your one-on-one coaching is
only two thousand dollars okay so
understand this my boundary is further
away from me because I'm charging more
money
people can't get access to me unless
they pay at that place and so it's
directly related to the boundaries of
how much we allow other people to use us
and walk all over us and take advantage
of us in our business
and listen if you're somebody who gets
satisfaction from helping other people
which by the way I am as well I wouldn't
be doing what I do if that wasn't the
case but if you sacrifice yourself your
family your finances in order to help
others
and you constantly allow people to
encroach upon you
to the point that they become a burden
to you
that's a boundaries issue okay and so
what we're doing is we're allowing other
people you know some people have no
boundaries and so they will just coach
people for free
and what's interesting is when they
finally set boundaries they start
charging the people who got free access
to them will complain they'll whine
they'll be upset they'll be angry they
might even
criticize scrutinize and demonize you
for setting a boundary on your access to
you I had this happen to me myself is
that when I started charging what I do
to get access to me I had offered people
they could schedule free calls with me
free 15-minute calls and I told
everybody you can direct message me for
free I have open DMS anything you need
help with I got you I'm here for you
and I set a boundary to where no longer
would I do free calls
and no more DMS for for coaching and
advice no private advice like that
and it shows because people got angry
that I no longer offered that and I said
you're gonna have to if you have
questions Listen by the way if you're
listening to this I still provide if you
go post on my YouTube channel if you
comment on my social media
if you're in my coaching group and you
ask a question to help you I will answer
you and I will help you and I'll guide
you through those things
but I don't do private coaching that
takes my time away in a one-on-one
setting level with anybody who pays less
than fifteen thousand dollars minimum
to do so and I have a group coaching
program that's two thousand dollars so
my boundary expanded
to the level of access that I was
allowing people to come and get access
to me
and so we have to a set those and stick
to them if you're constantly allowing
people to encroach upon them you don't
really have a boundary and you may need
to ask yourself why am I letting people
treat me that way and why am I
disrespecting Myself by allowing other
people to disrespect me to get free
access to me free access to coaching
whatever that is
and so with this this is why now when we
show up
as somebody gets angry and says you know
there's no way you could ever expect
anybody to pay you two thousand dollars
to work with you what kind of crazy
person are you
you have a decision I have a decision in
that moment do I let this person decide
where my boundary is for me
and some people would because they don't
want the conflict they don't want the
interaction they don't want the
negativity
that's where you need to strengthen your
ability to have boundaries of what
you're willing to give up
in your life you know we have to have
this when it comes to our morals and our
integrity
we have to have this in in a number of
different areas of our life
but when it comes to building our
business I find that people disrespect
themselves more than anything else more
than any other area because they're
trying to get validation from other
people they're trying to get people to
like them
and they struggle to express the limits
of where people can get access because a
lot of times they're so desperate to be
seen and heard
I'm so desperate for people to just see
my value
that I'm willing to sacrifice my
boundary and now I have no value
and I'm showing up
as somebody who is just looking to get
validation and nobody will invest in
that and now you don't have a business
and that's the situation that most
mentors and trainers and coaches find
themselves in is without a business
because they're giving away so much of
themselves for free
or Dirt Cheap to people and they have no
respect for themselves because they're
just seeking approval from others as
payment
how many of y'all have done that listen
I've done it I'm just I'm gonna be
straight up with you I have done this
for way too long and enough is enough
and I'm done with it and I'm done giving
up
what's valuable that I have that's
special
that when people come into my space I
help them become millionaires
and I'm not going to give that up for
free or cheap just because somebody else
doesn't see my value or thinks they are
entitled to me because I can help them
yeah and you'll have people they will
try to beat you up knock you down try to
tell you that you're not worth what
you're asking for
and this is why what you believe in
yourself
is what determines how much money you
can make if you don't believe that
you're worth worth it you'll give
yourself up to the first person who
gives you validation
you know honestly this sounds like a
training that I would teach to
um teenagers and young people about
dating as well
you'll give yourself up to the first
person to show you attention
and and we find by the way by the way
that was that was me when I was younger
a teenager
and and so in that that same thing we
end up bringing into the same way we
would in romantic settings we end up
bringing into our coaching
and we don't respect ourselves
and and we and and if somebody can just
say the right things they can get us to
give up our values
for just a small moment of validation
and and we know that that doing that in
in romantic relationships is it's not
healthy and it's not healthy at all in a
business setting either it's not healthy
even in a
family relationship
at that point and so boundaries are so
important to be able to express
to stick to to hold to
and that helps you determine
what you're willing to charge in your
business if we're having the
conversation about pricing for your
mentoring for your coaching we have to
first have the conversation of are you
so desperate for other people's approval
first
for other people using you
for other people taking advantage of you
and I get it I used to be that person I
was like please if I just want somebody
to take advantage of me
I have I have so much to offer but
nobody's seeing it and I was desperate
to be seen and heard by others so much
so
that I devalued myself to zero in
business
even though I had built multi-million
dollar businesses
and I would bet and challenge you that
if you're listening to this right now
you might be doing the same thing in
your own business you might be doing the
same thing in your life and it's time
to stop to grow
charge 50 to 100 more than you are if
you're charging 100 bucks right now
charge 150 to 200. next time you get a
client
oh Jeremiah I'm not ready for that today
great do it in two months give yourself
a 60-day countdown by the way this might
become a great sale for you to get some
clients
listen y'all I'm raising my prices in 60
days they're gonna be double but you can
you can grab it now that's a way to
inject cash into your business right
there
okay we've done that multiple times by
the way but you have to have boundaries
and you have to be willing to stick to
your guns even when people try to
discredit you even when people try to
tell you that you don't have value I had
people hop on the phone with me and tell
me Jeremiah if your system's so damn
good then you would give it to me for
free and I wouldn't have to pay and so
the fact that you're charging is proof
that it's worthless literally that's
what they told me and I'm like what in
the world kind of gaslighting and
craziness is this but that's what will
happen in business that's what happens
in business is that people will try to
show up to get you to give up your
values
to them
so that they can actually benefit from
it and then they'll kick you to the
street
with no respect for you because they
don't have respect for you and they
don't have respect for somebody that's
willing to give themselves up that quick
now here's the thing I've never had
those people come back to pay me what
I'm worth either
and so for me if somebody's gonna treat
me that way they've automatically
disqualified themselves from doing
business with me especially if they do
it two or three times and I've gotten
some emails from people
there's even some of y'all that are
listening to this podcast that I've
gotten emails from and and and and and
as you can tell from my response I
clearly don't
um listen to it I I mean I do read it I
see it that's why I made a podcast about
this topic because I think it's so
valuable I think that people need to
understand this and that if you're a
mentor if you're a coach if you're a
thought leader if you're a trainer you
need to get this and not allow it to
control you to where you let other
people's opinions if somebody tells you
you're not worth XYZ that you lower your
standards down to meet them for their
validation instead of that realize that
you need to raise the value that you
offer first off and also become really
good at communicating that value to
people
and so that was my issue that I
struggled with is I struggled to
actually communicate that value with
confidence I struggled to actually with
the words that I said and how I would
show up
um in my business and by the way that
had nothing to do with how I was dressed
I've actually dressed down a lot in my
business and I find that when I dress
down
so there's a positive Financial benefit
for me
and so in that
I'm paying attention to
who is becoming paid clients of mine who
is actually joining me who is actually
coming into my space and I'm paying
attention to okay what are they
struggling with how can I help them how
can I provide value that's why this
podcast exists this is to provide value
resources tips tricks help and things
that are going to help you make more
money in your business now in our client
growth accelerator coaching program we
go a lot deeper into that with the
courses that are in there with the
discussions that we have
and so if you have an opportunity to
join the client growth accelerator make
sure to get on the waiting list jump
into it at the time of this recording
it's only two thousand dollars a year
but it will go up in the future okay
don't wait on taking action to actually
build a mentorship business that can
make you six and seven figures
start to move the needle forward for
yourself and start to do the things that
are going to make the real difference
and one of those big things is
your ability
to hold to your boundaries to stick to
them to not let people walk all over
them to not let other people decide for
you
what your boundaries are
and let yourself be the one that decides
even if people get upset even if they
get angry even if they
try to paint you as the enemy
that you don't waver
that you don't
let others treat you and mistreat you
that way
and that you focus on those that are
celebrating you that are
enjoying working with you
and maybe you're listening to saying
Jeremiah I got nobody I got nobody
celebrating me I got nobody as a client
how can everybody's just negative and
nobody sees my value
it starts by you seeing your value
yourself first
it starts by you seeing your worth first
there's a great book called you are a
badass by Jen sincero that can help with
some of that
seeing that you're absolutely incredible
and worth people working with and worth
people spending money investing into
just as you are right now
you're not looking for validation from
others to tell you that you're worth
something
take it from me
in my business and my experience
in the last 12 months we've earned over
a million dollars in our business
that it wasn't until I started seeing my
value and asking for it
and not giving myself up to people
I stopped a year and a half ago
doing free calls with people
and that immediately sparked
for about six months I didn't see any
more cash flow come in it was like dead
zone
when it came to actually money when I
did that I had to go through a dead zone
of no sales because I was getting some
clients through the free calls but there
was only like 500 to 1000 bucks a month
then I had to go through a dead zone
when I got rid of that and then I
launched my group coaching program and
that's what's generated that that
million dollars for us
and so understanding that you might have
to go through a season where your
biggest fear actually becomes a reality
you might not get business during that
time
you might have to put some things in
order
and and do the thing that terrifies you
the most
because on the other side of that is the
dreams that you have and start
visualizing the dream life that you want
what is that dream life and dream future
that you want for you and your family
start to see it in your mind's eye
and then start doing the things that'll
get you there
that's why this podcast is here to help
you do that that's why my client growth
accelerator is there to help you do that
I'm here for you
and I can't wait to see you go to the
next level
grow your life everybody share this
podcast with somebody
we'll talk soon have a good one
[Music]